Ada Peirce McCormick papers, 1881-1978 (bulk 1920-1974)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Ada Peirce McCormick papers, 1881-1978 (bulk 1920-1974)
MS 327
McCormick, Ada Peirce, 1888-1974
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence to and from Ada Peirce McCormick relating to her family, friends and business ventures. Of particular interest are the letters contained in the Correspondence, Cabot Files and Tarbell Files series as they provide insight into the attitudes, character and pursuits of Ada Peirce McCormick and provide a good source of biographical material.
54 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Ada Stetson Peirce was born in Bangor, Maine, on March 28, 1888, to Mellen C. and Ann Hayford Peirce. The youngest of four children, she grew up in a prosperous and conservative environment. Ada's post-secondary education included the Ogontz School, Garland School of Homemaking, Boston School of Social Workers, a brief stint at Radcliffe, and the University of Arizona, where she earned a degree in 1932. In 1912, while in Williamsport, Pennsylvania, she met Fred Culver McCormick through a mutual acquaintance. The two married on July 31, 1915, after carrying on a long-distance romance. They moved to Williamsport where Fred worked in his father's insurance business. From 1925 to 1930, Ada gave lectures on marriage and homemaking at various eastern colleges, establishing a national reputation.
The McCormicks relocated to Tucson, Arizona, in 1931 for health reasons. Fred joined the University of Arizona faculty as Professor of English and served as the managing editor of the Arizona Quarterly. In 1937, Ada Peirce McCormick (APM) started the Chapel of Wandering Scholars near the University of Arizona. It later became Cabot Chapel and, in 1954, was incorporated as the non-denominational Little Chapel of All Nations to "promote the God-seeking impulses in mankind."
APM was active in community affairs on a number of different fronts. In 1942, she lobbied to create a recreational facility in Tucson for African-American soldiers, an effort that met with heated opposition from many Tucsonans. The Negro United Service Organization presented her with a commendation for her controversial work. APM's passion for social justice and human rights prompted her to found Letter, a national quarterly devoted to promoting dialogue on national and international problems and to better relationships between individuals and nations. The first issue appeared in January, 1943. Although it soon became an irregular quarterly, subsequent issues contained works by noted authors and APM editorials on relationships and international concerns. Letter gave numerous awards to individuals in various fields for their moral courage, intellect and devotion to country. The last issue was printed in 1948.
A published author and prolific letter writer, APM conducted research on myriad issues and corresponded with many of the social and political leaders, academics, industry executives, and literary figures of her time. Over the years APM received many awards and recognitions for her accomplishments, including, in 1960, the University of Arizona 75th Anniversary Medallion for her religious work with students. Preceded in death by her husband, APM passed away August 4, 1974. For additional information on her life, see: Ada: The Biography of a Woman Ahead of Her Time, by Roger J. O'Mara. (Call number, F29 B2 M36 1988).
Organization
This collection is organized into eleven series:
Note on arrangement: The Ada Peirce McCormick Collection, when received, was well-ordered with the material falling logically into several record sets, or series. Since most of the record creator's original file headings provided an accurate description of the folder contents, they have been retained. However, some of the contents were rearranged for clarity in order to satisfy external research needs. Because correspondence is the dominant record type found in the collection and the contents relate to a broad range of topics, it did not seem logical to group them all under one series titled "Correspondence." Rather, letters are arranged within the appropriate series with the correspondents duly noted. The archivist feels that this will not affect the overall integrity of the collection, but facilitate future use.
Series I: Correspondence, Ada Peirce McCormick (APM) and Fred Culver McCormick (FCM), 1903-1976
Series II: General Files, ca. 1915-1978
Series III: Cabot Files, 1899-1975
Series IV: Tarbell Files, 1891-1968
Series V: Manuscripts, 1906-1950
Series VI: APM Articles and Research, 1926-1962
Series VII: Business Activities, 1939-1968
Series VIII: Poetry and Drawings, 1915-1971
Series IX: Photographs, ca. 1887-1974
Series X: Teacher Files, 1913-1942
Series XI: Biographical Files, 1915-1976
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence to and from APM relating to her family, friends and business ventures. Of particular interest are the letters contained in the Correspondence, Cabot Files and Tarbell Files series as they provide insight into the attitudes, character and pursuits of APM and provide a good source of biographical material.
See the series descriptions below for a fuller narrative of each.
McCormick, Fred Culver, 1885- -- Correspondence; Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973 -- Correspondence; Cabot, Ella Lyman -- Correspondence; Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), -- 1868-1939; De Grazia, Ted, 1909- -- Correspondence; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958 -- Correspondence; Herzog, Arthur -- Correspondence; Kirmse, Evelyn Jones -- Correspondence; Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-1970 -- Correspondence; Pack, Arthur Newton, 1893- -- Correspondence; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962 -- Correspondence; Udall, Morris K. -- Correspondence; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975 -- Correspondence; Tarbell, Ida M. (Ida Minerva), 1857-1944 --Correspondence.; Little Chapel of All Nations (Tucson, Ariz.); Correspondence; Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, Ada Peirce McCormick (APM) and Fred Culver McCormick (FCM), 1903-1976
  Contains eleven rolls of microfilm. Rolls 1-5 consist of APM's business and personal correspondence from 1942-1974. Roll 1 includes an index to correspondence from April, 1947, to February, 1961. Roll 5 ends with news clippings and write-ups on the life of APM that span the years 1912-1976. Rolls 6 to 8 contain correspondence between APM and FCM (1912-1966). Found in these files are their love letters, plans for marriage, discussions on their faults and good points, and thoughts on religion. Rolls 9 to 11 comprise correspondence between FCM, friends, and relatives (1903-1965).
  - Index to APM correspondence; APM correspondence. April 1947-February 1961, September 1942-September 1944 (Box 1, Reel 1)
  - APM correspondence. October 1944-January 1948 (Box 1, Reel 2)
  - APM correspondence. February 1948-December 1951 (Box 1, Reel 3)
  - APM correspondence. January 1952-September 1960 (Box 1, Reel 4)
  - APM correspondence; clippings. October 1960-1961, 1912-1976 (Box 1, Reel 5)
  - FCM and Ada S. Peirce correspondence. 1912-October 1915 (Box 1, Reel 6)
  - FCM and APM correspondence. 1916-November 1935 (Box 1, Reel 7)
  - FCM and APM correspondence. February 1936-1966 (Box 1, Reel 8)
  - FCM correspondence. 1903-1935 (Box 1, Reel 9)
  - FCM correspondence. 1935-1947 (Box 1, Reel 10)
  - FCM correspondence. 1948-1965 (Box 1, Reel 11)
  - Index to APM correspondence. April 1947-December 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Index to APM correspondence. January 1951-February 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: General Files, ca. 1915-1978
  Constitutes the bulk of material in the collection and reflects APM's diverse interests, her involvement in activities at the local, national, and international levels, as well as her career as a writer and editor. Materials include correspondence, drawings, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, photographs, and printed material. Much of the correspondence is between APM and authors who submitted poems and stories for publication in Letter. The researcher will note that some of the materials are dated after APM's death in 1974. In these cases the items are most often correspondence from one of APM's employees and deals with closure on a specific concern or issue.
  - A: Miscellaneous. 1942-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, Richard G., research reports on advertising. 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Acme Printing Co. 1943-1951 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Acton family records. 1938-1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Acton, Floyd. 1948-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Acton, Mary Louise. 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Adair, Price. 1949-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Adamic, Louis. 1942-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Adams, George J. 1959-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Addams, Jane and Hull House. 1929-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Adler, Elmer A. 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Adobe & Mesquite. 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Adventures in Business. 1947 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Advertising, meetings and ads. 1942-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - African Methodist Episcopal Church. 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Afro-American Newspapers. 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Agnew, Mrs. P.G., race discrimination. 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Agriculture, United States Department of. 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Extension Service. 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Alba, Nanina C. 1955-1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Albert, John Henry Greenway. 1948-1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Albertson, Grace. 1945-1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Albertson, Grace, interviews in New York for APM. 1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Alkus, Mrs Robert (Mary). 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Alkais, Mrs. Charles (Edith). 1945-1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Allbee, Lewis. 1939-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Allderdice, Norman. 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Allen, Charles. 1947-1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Allen Edward W. (Seattle lawyer re: Chinese, Japanese, Dulles, etc.). 1943-1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Allen, James. 1953-1965 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Allen's Press Clipping Bureau. 1948-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ambrose, Robert. 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - America (Jesuit Magazine). 1952-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - American Antiquarian Society. 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - American Association for United Nations, Inc. 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - American Association of University Women. 1943-1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - American China Policy Association. 1946-1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - American Civil Liberties Union and Roger Baldwin. 1943-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom. 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - American Committee for Emigre Scholars and Writers. 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - American Committee on Africa. 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - American Council for Better Broadcasting. 1963 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American Council on Education. 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Labor. 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - American Foundations Information Service. 1951-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - American Friends Service Committee, K. Peckham. 1942-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - American Genetic Association. 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - American Indian Fund. 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - American Institute for Foreign Trade. 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - American Institute on Management. 1951-1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - American Jewish Committee. 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - American Legion and Auxiliary. 1941-1967 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - American Library Association (ALA). 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - ALA Awards. 1945-1948 (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
  - ALA Awards. 1948-1956 (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
  - ALA (compilation of librarian and library awards). 1946-1956 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - American Magazine. 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - American Medical Women's Association. 1949 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - American Medical Association. 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - American Mercury. 1946, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - American Negro Emancipation Centennial Authority. 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - American Psychological Association. 1950-1961 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - American Red Cross (Tucson chapeter). 1940-1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - American Relief for India. 1945 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - American Scholar. 1948-1953 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - American Scientist. 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - American Social Hygiene Association. 1926-1952 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Americans United for World Organization and Government. 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Amerind Club, University of Arizona. ca. 1958-1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Amigos de las Americas. 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Amrine, Michael, Mr. and Mrs. 1946-1952 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Amyx, Hurst B. 1961 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Anderegg, Bruno H. 1952 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Anderson, Arthur Olaf. 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Andersen, Helen (Mrs. Edmund E.). 1943-1947 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Andhra Research University & Eloy Alfaro of Ecuador. 1944 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Andreeva, Tamara. 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Andrews, Lawrence. 1943-1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Angleton, Cicely D'Autremont. 1935-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Anglican Theological Review and Anglican Digest. 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Anselm Forum. 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Anthony, Lucille B. 1943 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Anthony, Mary. 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith. 1945-1949 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Antioch Review. 1945-1954 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Antiquarian Bookman. 1955-1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Appeals and Proposals. 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Applebaum, Harold. 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Appelman, Morris. 1966 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Appleton (D.) Century, Inc. 1947 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Applications for Secretary to APM. 1939 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Applications for various types of jobs. 1939-1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Arden, Elizabeth. 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Arendt, Hannah. 1954 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Arizona Academy of Science. 1962-1967 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Arizona Alumnus re: write-up on APM and Letter. February 1945 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Arizona and the West. 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Arizona Board of Pardon and Paroles. 1949 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Arizona Childrens Home Association. 1940-1967 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Arizona Church Record. 1960 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Arizona Congress of Parents and Teachers. 1950-1955 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Arizona Daily Star. 1942-1974 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Arizona Desert School. 1950-1954 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Arizona Dispatch (Negro newspaper). 1960 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Arizona Education Association. 1947-1967 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Arizona Highways. 1945-1952 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Migrant Ministry. 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Arizona motion picture corporation. 1942 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Arizona's Negro Journal. 1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ariozona newspaper association. 1953-1973 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Arizona Pioneers' Historical Society. 1948-1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Arizona Press Clipping bureau. 1942 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Arizona Quarterly. 1945-1963 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Arizona Sonora Desert Museum. 1959-1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Arizona State College, Tempe, Matthews Library. 1945-1954 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Arizona Business and Professional directory. 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Arizona State Fair commission. 1947 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Arizona State Federation of Labor. 1943 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Arizona State Game and Fish Commission. 1963 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Arizona State Legislature. 1949-1954 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Arizona State Library Association. 1939-1973 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Arizona State School for the Deaf and Blind. 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Arizona's Who's Who. 1948-1953 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Armstrong, Mrs. Donald B. 1943 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Armstrong, Margaret. 1943 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Arnold, Elliot. No date (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Arnold, Julean. 1943 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Aryan Path (Mrs. Maud Paige). 1946 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Asia and the Americas. 1944 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Association for Applied Solar Energy. ca. 1955 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Association for the Chinese Blind. 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Association for Papago Affairs. 1955-1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Associated Press. 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Associated Publishers, Inc. 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Astor, Lady Nancy. 1943-1948 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Monthly. 1920-1971 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Energy. 1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Auchincloss, Douglas. 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Australian Quarterly. 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Authors Guild and Authors League. 1942-1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ayer Directory. 1943-1953 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Aylward, Dagh. 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - B: Miscellaneous, Ba-Bl. 1942-1947 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - B: Miscellaneous, Bo-By. 1942-1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Bacon's Clipping Bureau. 1955-1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Bailey, Mrs. Clifford (Ellen). 1923-1970 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Bailly, Pierre L. 1950 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Baitsell, George. 1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Baitsell, George. 1953-1961 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Bakalyar, Florence. 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Baker, Elizabeth. 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard. 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Balascheff, Mary. 1928-1930 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Balch, Franklin G. 1945 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Baldwin, Milton. 1943-1947 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Ballenger, Maurice. 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Bandel, Betty. 1944-1970 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Banigan, Father Robert A. 1949 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Banks, Camille Weare. 1945-1953 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Barlow, Debbie Brighton. 1970 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Barr, Reverend Stewart. 1960-1965 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Barrett, Mrs. Robert. 1945-1952 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Barron's. 1942-1968 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Barthel, Oliver. 1943-1948 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Bartlett, Vernon. 1931-1942 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Barton, Bruce. 1945 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Bass, Jerry. 1946-1950 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Bass, Edith and Robert. 1933-1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bass, Edith and Robert. 1944-1946 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bass, Edith and Robert. 1947-1960 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Bauder, Jean. 1947-1958 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Beacon Press. 1947-1956 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Beardsley, Phyllis. 1947 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Beaumont, Hugh. 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Becker, Benjamin. 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Becker, Edwin. 1945-1954 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Becker, Dr. R. Fredrick. 1945 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Bellows, Silence Buck. 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Benedict, Ruth. 1945-1965 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Bennett, Katherine. 1943-1946 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Bennett, Mrs. Claude. 1929-1943 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Bennett, James V. 1943, 1960-1961 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Bennett, Paulina. 1947-1967 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Bennion, Lowell. 1960 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Benson, Flynn Clark. 1945-1948 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Benton, Patricia. 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Berea College (Francis Hutchins). 1948-1973 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Bernays, Edward. 1942 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Berninger, Claire. 1954-1957 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Best, Pauline. 1947-1952 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bhattacharys, Bhabani. 1950-1952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Bibliographical Center for Research. 1952-1955 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Biddle, Mrs. Francis. 1946-1949 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Biddle, Randy. 1946-1951 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bilby Richard. 1967 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Bilgray, Rabbi Albert T. 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Binder, Carroll. 1944-1947 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Biography lectures. 1950 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Bird, Charles Sumner. 1942-1949 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Bird, Marjorie. 1948-1950 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Birthright Inc. 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Black Mountain College. 1944-1946 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Blacklidge, Frank and Frances. 1938-1973 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Blackwell's. 1950-1952 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Blacklist of institutions. 1953 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Bois, Dr. J.S.A. 1949-1953 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Boni, Albert and Charles. 1948-1949 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Booker, Mary Russell. 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Book of the Month Club. 1941-1950 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Books Abroad. 1945 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Borgese, G.A. and Elizabeth Mann. 1947-1949 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Boston Library. 1954, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Bostic, Private William P., re: Negro USO. 1941-1946 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Bottome, Phyllis. 1951-1952 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Bousfield, Colonel M.O. 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Boyle, James and Jane Boyle Needham. 1951-1965 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Bragg, Mrs. J.D. 1948 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Brand, Frances Clarke. 1934-1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Brandes School. 1952-1954 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Brandt, Lillian and sister Genevieve. 1923-1956 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Branson, Helm Kitchen. 1948-1958 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Breasted, Martha and Charles. 1939-1966 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Bretall, Dr. Robert W. 1956-1967 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Breuer, Bessie. 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Brewer, Dr. Willis. 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Bridges, Ronald. 1942-1946 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Briarcliff Junior College. 1943-1946, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - British Book Center. 1951-1957 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Brinegar, David F. 1954-1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - British Information Services. 1940-1961 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - British Publications. 1942-1958 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Britton, Captain Dan. 1937-1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Brodbeck, Arthur. 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Brodek, Charles S. 1943-1947 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bross, Mrs. John (Joan). 1943-1958 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Beulah. 1950 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Brown, Francis T. 1942-1952 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Brown, George Dobbin. 1943-1949 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Brown, James W. 1943-1945 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Brownlee Sisters and Russell Brownlee. 1954-1969 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Bryant, Chester. 1950 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Buck, Pearl. 1943-1965 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Buckley, William F. 1951-1952 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Buckley, William F. 1951-1974 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Bucknell University. 1927-1950 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Bullock, Alice. 1951-1953 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Burch, Mrs. Bradley. 1950-1953 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Burch, Mrs. Robert. 1948-1954 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Burch, Thula. 1951 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Bull, J.C. Inc. 1946 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Burrell, Dr. David D. 1945-1947 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Button, Henry (J.M. Dent and Sons). 1943-1952 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Buzzell, Lucille. 1945-1949 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Bye, George. 1944-1948 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Byers, Calvin. 1946-1950 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Bynner, Witter. 1943-1947 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Byrne, Carlton. 1959-1964 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Byron, William F. 1949 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - C: Miscellaneous. 1924-1969 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Cabat-Gill Advertising Agency. 1946-1951 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, Jr. 1949 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Caldwell, June. 1948-1961 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Caldwell, Dr. Mary E. 1952-1964 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Campbell, Rachel Harris. 1949-1953 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Canaan Reporter (Edward Androvette). 1950 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Canby, Mrs. Henry S. 1946 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Cantril, Hadley. 1944 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Capital Punishment. 1961 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Capp, Al. 1956-1971 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Capuchin Annual. 1952 (Box 16, Folder 2)